good afternoon everybody welcome good to
下午 好 欢迎 大家 好
see you so this week we're going to
看你因此本周我们将
study how to incorporate concurrency
研究如何将并发
into into programs now we've seen
进入到程序现在我们已经看到了
concurrent concurrency before in the
在之前的并发并发
form of Prophecy exception handlers and
预言异常处理的形式和
in the in the case of processes it was
在中的处理的情况下它是
immaculate we used we used prophecies as
完美无暇的，我们 用我们 用预言作为
the mechanism to run multiple
该机制运行多个
independent application program okay now
独立的应用程序现在没事了
but you could concurrency also exists in
但你可以 并发还 存在 于
application programs now we've seen a
应用程序现在我们已经看到了
little bit of this only when we studied
这 一点 只有 当我们研究
signal handlers okay so a signal handler
信号处理 好这样一个 信号处理器
is that is a concurrent flow that runs
是运行并发流
concurrently with your with your main
同时与你与你的主
application program okay and we've seen
应用程序可以的，我们已经看到了
we've seen how some of the difficulties
我们已经看到了如何一些 困难
that can arise when we introduce
当 我们介绍 可能出现
concurrency in our programs so even with
并发在我们的计划，使即使有
something like a signal handler which
类似的信号处理器，其
isn't doing very much it's very hard for
没有做 很多这是非常困难的
us to reason about this kind of this
我们来思考 这种 本
kind of thing when we have two two
之类 的话 时，我们有二两
concurrent flows running at the same
在相同的运行并发流
time like there's our brains just tend
像有一次是我们的大脑往往只
to be kind of sequential we want to
是一种 连续的，我们要
think about things happening one after
想想事情 发生后一个
the other you know it is and it's much
另外 ，你知道这是和它的多
easier for us to reason about that
我们更容易 推论说
reasoning about multiple things
推理多件事情
happening at the same time really causes
发生在同一时间真的 会导致
problems and that the fundamental reason
问题和根本原因
is that - really - really reason about
是-真-真推理
say - two independent two concurrent
说-两个独立的两个并行
flows we have to account for all of the
流向我们必须考虑所有的
possible interleavings of those flows
这些流的可能的交错
okay and that's where and that's that
好吧 ，这就是在那里， 就是这样
grows exponentially with the feed with
配合饲料与指数增长
the number of flows okay so you had you
流的数量好吧 ，你有你
saw this with your signal handlers when
看到这个与你的信号处理程序时，
you did shell lab you had you had two
你没有外壳实验室你有你有两个
concurrent flows the main program and
并发流主程序和
and your signal handler both accessing a
和信号处理程序都访问
shared resource in the form of a
在的形式共享资源
the jobs list right and you had to be
作业列表中的权利，你必须是
very careful to prevent an interleaving
非常小心，以 防止交织
where that where that data structure was
如该其中该数据结构是
being referenced in an inconsistent
在 不一致的被引用
state okay so what we're going to do
状态 好了，所以我们要做的
this week and into next week is we're
本周到下周，是我们
going to we're going to look at that
要我们要去 看看那个
kind of application level concurrency
各种应用级别的并发
but in a more principled in a more
但在一个更加原则性的更
principled way than we encountered with
比我们遇到了原则的方式
with signal handlers so as soon as you
与信号处理函数，以便只要你
have multiple flows accessing shared
已经多个流访问共享
resources all kinds of bad things can
资源各种不好的 东西 可以
happen in your program and these these
发生在你的 程序和这些这些
have been these these bad things these
已经这些 这些不好的东西，这些
problems that occurred then objects of
发生那么的对象问题
study and computer science for four
研究和计算机科学四个
decades but the the kinds of things that
几十年来， 但 种 的东西，
can happen are races which we've seen in
可能 发生，我们 在 看到有比赛
when we did the shell lab where the the
当我们做了壳的实验室，其中的
outcome whether good or bad outcome
结果， 不管是好的还是坏的结果
depends on some some arbitrary
取决于一些一些任意
scheduling decision right in the case of
调度权的情况下决定
you know one of the races we saw in the
你知道 我们在看到比赛之一
case of a shell was the case where the a
壳的情况下， 是 的情况下一个
child just because of a scheduling
孩子仅仅 因为一个调度
decision by the kernel of runs and
通过运行的内核决定，
finishes before the parent has a chance
完成家长有机会之前
to add that child to the jobs list okay
给孩子添加到任务列表中 好
so that's that's a classic example of a
所以这是这是一个经典的例子
race and similarly if you have two
种族和同样，如果你 有两个
people that are trying to making
那些试图 使 人们
accessing a reservation system on a bird
访问对鸟预约系统
for an airline
为航空公司
who gets the if they both access at the
谁得到在该如果他们都访问
same time who actually gets a seat just
究竟是谁得到一个座位正好同一时间
depends on various scheduling decisions
取决于不同的调度决策
that are going on in the reservation
在预约的事
system another kind of a problem that
系统另外一种问题， 那
occurs is deadlock so a deadlock is a
发生死锁是 这样一个僵局是
condition that exists where you have
存在，你必须条件
multiple flows waiting for an event that
多个流等待一个事件
will never occur okay so using printf in
所以用printf将不会发生好吗
a signal handler is an example of this
的信号处理程序是这样的一个例子
kind of of this kind of problem or
的一种这样那样的问题，或者
introduces the potential for that kind
介绍了潜在的那种
of problem
问题
okay so in your main routine UX you
好了，所以在你的主程序 UX你
execute a printf and that printf
执行一个printf 和printf的
acquires a lock on some system resource
获得一些系统资源的锁定
I I think it's a terminal lock and then
我 我认为 这是一个终端 锁，然后
after that that main printf acquires
之后是主要获取的printf
that lock it gets interrupted by signal
这个锁它被通过 信号 中断
handler and now the signal handler if it
处理器和现在的信号处理程序 ，如果它
does a printf that printf will try to
这是否将printf的尝试给 printf
acquire that lock but it won't be able
获得该锁，但它不能
to get it because the the printf in the
得到它，因为在对中的printf
main routine has it so now your signal
主程序所以现在有它的信号
ham the printf in the signal handler is
火腿的printf在信号处理程序是
waiting for an event that will never
等待事件永远不会
occur it's waiting for that lock to be
它发生在等待该锁是
released and it will never occur because
释放，它永远不会发生 ，因为
the main the printf in the main routine
在主程序主中的printf
can't release the lock until the signal
无法解除锁定， 直到 信号
handler returns and the signal handler
处理退货和信号处理程序
can't acquire the lock until the printf
无法获取锁，直到中的printf
in the main routine terminate so that's
在主程序终止所以这
that's a classic example of deadlock
这是僵局的一个典型的例子
another more from from real life imagine
另一个更来自现实生活中的 想象
that imagine that you're all drivers
那想象一下 ， 你是所有驱动程序
follow the rules very precisely and and
遵守规则 非常精确，并与
the rule for a four-way stop is that
对于 四路站 的规则 是，
whoever gets there first gets to go
谁抢先 获得去
first okay so if four cars arrive at the
第一好了，所以如果四个车在到达
intersection exactly the same time then
相交完全相同的时间，然后
you have a deadlock you have none of the
你已经死锁你有没有 的
drivers was first so no none of the
司机是第一次所以没有没有 的
drivers goes and so they're all waiting
司机去，所以他们都在等
for a condition that will never occur
对于 将永远不会 发生 的 条件
and then other classical things that can
然后等经典的东西，可以
go wrong or things like liveness
出问题或之类的东西活跃度
starvation fairness of this starvation
这个饥饿的 饥饿公平
occurs when you sail you're trying to do
当你驶向 你正在试图做的发生
something but you fail to make progress
的东西，但你无法取得进展，
because somebody else keeps getting all
因为别人不断得到所有
the work right so if you were if you had
工作权 ，所以如果你是，如果你 有
two processes and the kernel always
两个过程始终内核
scheduled process a instead of process B
调度处理的代替处理B的
process B that would be an example of
处理B，这将是 的 一个例子
process B being starved out because of a
处理B饿死因为一个出
improper scheduling decision and we
不正确的调度决策和我们
would say that that that's
要说的是，那这就是
policy always Schedule D is unfair right
政策总是附表D是不公平 的权利
so it doesn't have this this property of
所以它 不具备这个这个属性
fairness where every every entity in the
公平，每一个每一个实体在
system gets gets sort of a reasonable
系统得到得到某种合理的
chunk of the processor so like I said I
处理器的块所以像我说 我
mean this concurrency has been studied
这意味着并发性进行了研究
for years it's a very it's a very deep
多年来这是一个非常这是一个 非常深刻的
difficult topic because of this because
因为这一点，因为很难话题
of this sort of exponential explosion in
这种指数爆炸中
the number of interleavings so we can't
的交错的数量 ，所以我们不能
we're not going to cover all of them on
我们不打算覆盖所有的人都在
but we will cover some so as you get a
但是，我们将介绍一些使你得到一个
reasonable idea of that how to
那合理的想法如何
incorporate concurrency in your programs
合并并发在你的程序
now for for our study of application
现在我们的应用研究
level concurrency we're going to use
级并发，我们要使用
servers as a motivating example and and
服务器作为激励例子 和和
the reason is that you cannot write a
其原因是，你可以不写
correct server without using concurrency
正确的服务器，而无需使用并发
so it's a good it's a really good good
所以这是一个很好的它是一个 非常不错的好
motivation and here's the reason so so
动机和这里的原因， 所以这样
far we've looked at servers that are
到目前为止，我们已经看了那些服务器
iterative okay so they only they only
迭代好了，所以他们也 只是他们
process requests from one client at a
从一个客户端进程请求
time and once they finish processing or
时间，一旦他们完成处理或
request from a client then they go on to
从客户端 之后，他们去 申请
the next client so they so like with our
下一个客户端，以便他们这么喜欢我们的
iterative echo server you can see the
迭代回声服务器，你可以看到
each each of these clients makes a
每个这些客户 使得
connection request then it writes a line
连接请求 然后将它 写入一个线
of text to the server and then it waits
文本到服务器， 然后等待
for the server to echo that back and in
服务器呼应在背部 和
this case this simple case it just then
这种情况下，这个简单的情况下，就在这时，
it just closes okay and the server waits
它只是关闭好和服务器等待
for a connection request and accept and
用于连接请求，并接受与
then and then waits waits for and then
然后再等待等待再
once it accepts that connection requests
一旦接受连接 请求
it it reads and waits for what waits for
它读取并等待对于等待什么
that client to to to write something to
该客户端对 写 东西
the connection and then it echoes it
该连接，然后呼应它
back and then it and then it waits
回来，然后，然后等待
for the next nine until the until the
对于未来九个月， 直到 ，直到
the client closes that that connection
客户端关闭该该连接
and then the server closes its
然后服务器关闭其
connection and then only then does it
连接，然后才做它
does it do another except to wait for
它做的是另除了等待
the next connection request okay so in
下一个连接请求 好了，所以在
in in this example client two is also
在本实施例的客户端 2也是
making a connection request but it never
建立连接的 请求 ，但它 从来没有
it never runs it has to wait until the
它从来没有运行 它必须等待，直到
server actually echoes back the response
服务器实际上回显应答
now there's there's a little subtlety
现在有有一点点微妙
here that in where exactly that this
在这里，在正是这
client Waits so the the semantics of
客户等待 这样 的语义
Connect you would think that Connect
连接 你会认为 连接
would block until the connection was
将阻塞，直到连接 是
established but actually if you tried
成立但实际上，如果你试图
this out it turns out that Connect
这一点， 事实证明， 连接
actually initiates the connection
实际上发起连接
process inside the kernel but then it
在内核中，但随后的过程
returns okay before the the connection
在连接之前返回好吗
has been established and then it does a
已经建立 ，然后它做了
right and that right also returns
权，这种权利也回报
immediately right so it doesn't it
立即向右所以也 没有它
doesn't wait until the server reads that
不等到服务器将读取
the string that was written and it
这是书面和它的字符串
doesn't block until it it calls the read
不阻止 ，直到它调用读
function wait waiting for the echoed
功能等待 ， 等待回应
response from the server and so it
从服务器， 所以它响应
actually it doesn't block until it hits
实际上它不会阻止，直到遇到
this read and then it spends all it
这种阅读，然后花一切
waits waits waits waits and finally the
等待等待等待等待，终于
server accepts the connection request
服务器接受该连接请求
and then writes the writes the string
然后写入写入字符串
echoes the string back to the client
相呼应的字符串返回给客户端
so the the call to connect actually
因此调用实际连接
returns immediately and it exploits the
立即返回 ，它利用 了
feature in the kernel that can queue up
功能在内核中可以排队
these connection requests okay so that
这些连接请求 还好使
the kernel now is going through all the
内核现在正在经历的一切
process of setting up the connection but
建立连接的过程，但
the application program continues and
该应用程序将继续和
then the right the right inside the
再右边里面的右
client doesn't block because the the
客户端不会阻止，因为该
kernel can also queue up the data that's
内核还可以排队 是这样的数据
written so it'll it'll queue it up
书面所以它会，它会排队起来
remember that it was written when the
请记住，这是 写在
connection actually gets created then it
连接 实际上被创建 ，然后它
will it'll send that data along and but
将它会沿着发送数据，但
there's no way to avoid the the read
有没有办法避免读
from from blocking write a read can't
从阻塞写读不能
return until it gets some data okay so
返回，直到它得到了一些数据好了，
read has to block okay now here's the
读有权阻止现在没事了这里的
fundamental flaw of an iterative server
迭代服务器的 根本缺陷
and the reason the reason why we have to
而我们之所以有原因
write them using with with concurrency
他们与并发使用写
okay so let's say in our echo server
好了，让我们在我们的回声服务器说
example we have a client that creates a
例如，我们有一个创建一个客户端
connection request a connection it's
连接请求 这是 一个连接
accepted in the server does the write
在服务器接受不写
the server echoes back one you know one
服务器回送您知道的一个
string and then the client blocks again
字符串，然后在客户端的块再次
or instead of doing the next write or
或者不要 做下一个 写或
closing the connection the person it
关闭连接 的人就
the the user goes out to lunch and never
在用户外出吃午饭，从来没有
types in a string to these the echo
类型将字符串中的这些回波
client okay so at this point the server
客户好了 ，所以在这 一点上服务器
calls Reed and then it blocks waiting
调用里德，然后 等待块
for this user to type in something and
此用户在输入一些东西和
so that the client can send it to the
使客户可以将它发送到
server to be echoed but the user is gone
服务器中回荡，但用户已经一去不复返了
gets hit by a truck
被卡车撞
who knows anyway so this never this Reed
反正谁知道所以这 从来没有 这种里德
then blocks for an indeterminate amount
然后在不确定量块
of time right and while its blocking its
时间权，而 其阻断 其
client to which also wants service it
客户也希望 它 服务
has to block okay so now you're in an
有那么现在你 在 是阻止好吗
untenable situation where one client has
难以维持的局面，其中一个客户端
sort of totally affected all of the
那种完全影响了所有的
other clients in the system and none of
在系统中，没有其他客户
the other clients can get service so if
其他客户端可以得到 服务，所以如果
this were a web server if if one client
这是一个网络服务器，如果如果一个客户端
for some reason blocked no other no
出于某种原因堵塞 没有其他任何
other users would be able to to use that
其他用户将能够 使用该
web service or look at pages on that
在 对 网页的Web服务或看
step site so obviously this we can't
一步网站，所以这显然我们不能
have this okay so the solution is to use
有这样的好了，解决的办法是使用
this to write a concurrent server
这 写并发服务器
instead of an iterative server where
而不是迭代服务器里
we'll have a separate concurrent flow
我们将有一个独立的并发流
handle each client's request and
处理每一个客户的要求，
interact with each client so now if one
与每一个客户那么现在，如果一个互动
client for some reason is slow or
客户出于某种原因很慢或
misbehaves
行为不端
or blocks the system other clients won't
或块系统的其他客户端将无法
be affected because those clients will
受到影响，因为这些客户会
be handled like by concurrent flows
像通过并发流处理
so there are several ways a number of
所以有几种方法 的一些
ways to create these yes if you will
方法如果你愿意来创建这些是
from multiple class probably pay for
从多个类可能支付
life there other times negative put and
生活中 有其他时间负PUT和
there right over to make you all those
还有就 在 让你所有的
it actually could and in fact that
它实际上可能和事实
that's a form of concurrency okay so the
这是并发的形式 好 ，因此
question is could be because could the
问题是，可能是因为可以在
server queue up requests from from from
从从服务器排队的请求
clients it could but it would I guess
客户可能，但它会我猜
actually it would have to queue up it
实际上那就要排队 它
would somehow have to accept those
会在一定程度不得不接受那些
connections right so they know so that
连接权，让他们知道， 这样
wouldn't work so somehow you have since
不工作，所以在某种程度上你有自
the since the accept calls are iterative
在因为接听电话都是迭代
sequential there's no way to get data
顺序有没有办法得到数据
from those those other clients okay but
不同于其他客户 还可以，但
but actually what you're suggesting is
但实际上你是在暗示是
very similar to something called an
非常类似于一种叫做
event-based server that that will which
基于事件的 服务器，这将其
is one of the ways we can create
是 的，我们可以创建 一个 方法
concurrent flows so there's there's
并发流所以有有
there's three ways to to create these
有三种方法可以创建这些
concurrent flows one is to use
并发流一个是使用
prophecies okay like we've already seen
预言没关系就像我们已经看到的
okay so the kernel and so in this case
好了，所以 在这种情况下 ，内核等
the kernel handles all the scheduling
内核处理所有的调度
for us and in the leaves it it
对于美国和它，它的叶子
interleaves the process execution
交错流程执行
automatically for us and then as we saw
自动为我们，然后，我们看到
before each flow has its own private
之前每个流都有自己的私人
address space so that each flow is
地址空间中，使得 每个流是
independent and scheduled by the kernel
独立的，由内核调度
okay now there's a another another
还好现在有一个又一个的另一
approach called event based where the
基础的方法称为事件，其中
programmer manually interleaves the
程序员手动交织
flows okay so instead of relying on the
流动的好了，所以不是依靠
kernel to interleave these different
内核交错这些不同
flows that the user the programmer
流入该用户编程
creates this flows and then manually
创建该手动流动，然后
interleaves them okay
交错他们没关系
and since it's one program all of the
并且由于它是一个程序的所有
flows share the same address space right
流共享相同的地址空间 权
so they have access to all the same
所以他们可以访问所有相同
global data structures and they they do
全局数据结构和他们他们做
they do this interleaving using a
他们用这种交错
technique called IO multiplexing you
技术称为IO复用你
know I'll talk briefly about that but
知道我会 有关简要 谈 ，但
it's it's it's addressed much in much
这是它在很大程度上解决多
more detail on your book the the third
在 你的书的第三详细
approach which is kind of a hybrid of
方法这是一种混合的
process based and event based is thread
过程和基于事件线程
base so use each each each of these
碱所以使用每个各每个这些
flows is is implemented using something
流是用什么实现的
called a thread the kernel
被称为一个线程内核
like like prophesies the kernel
像预言一样的内核
automatically interleaves these these
自动交错这些这些
different threads
不同的线程
but unlike a process each each thread
但与每个每个线程的过程
shares the same address space okay so
共享相同的地址空间， 所以没关系
each thread has access to all the global
每个线程可以访问所有 全局
variables declared in the program so in
变量的程序，以便在申报
so it's like process based and that the
所以它就像基于过程， 而且
kernel on that automatically scheduled
对自动安排内核
it for us but it's like event based in
对我们来说 ，但它是基于像事件
the sense that every flow shares the
每一个流共享的意义
same address space
相同的地址空间
okay so we'll look let's look at all
好了，我们来看看让我们来看看所有
three of these approaches in more detail
三个详细介绍这些方法的
so the first approach is to create these
所以第一种方法是创建 这些
flows using processes so in this case
在这种情况下使用的过程，从而流
this is our echo server example the the
这 是我们的回声服务器例子的
client requests a connection and then
客户端请求连接，然后
calls F get s to wait for the user to
调用f得到s 到等待 用户
type something in at the at the keyboard
在键盘上输入的东西
but the user is gone and so F guest F
但用户 不见了 ， 因此 歼 客人˚F
get us this client just blocks in the
让我们这个客户端在只有几个街区
call to F get s so the server when it
打电话到F获得如此的服务器时，它
gets a request it accepts the connection
得到它接受连接的请求
requests and returns from the accept
从接受 请求 并返回
call
呼叫
and after it returns from the accept
并从返回后接受
call it Forks the child and then that
把它叉儿，然后说
child interacts that child process now
孩子现在交互子进程
will be responsible for interacting with
将负责 与互动
client number one so the child blocks
客户号一个，这样子块
waiting for data from client one which
等待来自客户端的一个数据，其
is never going to fill up because the
永远不会因为填补
the user left okay but it that's okay
用户留下 好的，但也没关系
because it doesn't stop the server the
因为它不会停止服务器
server after it Forks the child goes
之后服务器叉子云
right back and calls accept and now
右后卫和调用accept和现在
accept can accept the connection
接受可以接受的连接
requests from from client two and fork
从客户端两叉请求
off another a different child that can
掀起又一个不同的孩子 ，可以
interact with with client two so that
互动与客户端两条SO该
child will read waits for data to to
孩子会读的数据等待到
show up from the client and then it
从客户端显示出来，然后将其
echoes it back and at some point then
呼应回来，并在某些时候则
closes this connection okay so you see
好将关闭此连接，所以你看
that this misbehaving client number one
这个行为不端的客户端的头号
now because we have concurrent flows
现在因为我们有并发流
interacting with all the clients this
与所有的客户端 交互 此
misbehaving client can't adversely
行为不端的客户端不能不利
affect other clients okay so now that's
影响其他的客户还好所以现在这
and this is this idea of creating
这就是这个想法的创造
concurrent flows to to interact with
并发流，以进行交互
clients is is fundamental there you have
客户是根本的是有你有
to do this in order to to have sort of a
要做到这一点， 以便有排序 的
working server implementation alright so
工作服务器实现这样好吗
how would we actually program this
我们将如何实际设定此
process based concurrent server it's
基于过程的并行服务器是
actually surprisingly compact right
竟然出奇紧凑权
so we're going to pass in in art V we're
所以我们要通过在艺术 V WE是
going to pass in a port number that we
要在一个端口号来传递我们
want this server to listen on we've got
希望此服务器 侦听我们有
a listening descriptor and a connected
监听描述符和连接
descriptor we've got and then we've got
描述我们已经有了，然后我们有
a length and a an address address field
的长度和地址地址字段
and the the address is declared in a
而该地址是在声明
protocol independent way using this sock
使用这种袜子协议独立方式
out or storage type which is guaranteed
这是保证出或存储类型
to be big enough as you saw last time
必须足够大 ， 因为你看到的最后 一次
it's guaranteed to be big enough to
它的保证 是足够大到
handle any type of addressing there ipv4
处理任何类型的解决存在的 IPv4
or ipv6 okay so we install a sick child
或IPv6 好了，所以我们安装一个生病的孩子
handler and then we use the the open
处理程序，然后我们用 开放
listened FD a call from your from your
听了FD从您从您的通话
textbook to create a listening
教科书 建立一个监听
descriptor on port the port that we pass
描述端口，我们通过口
in as the as the argument to this
在作为作为参数来这
program and then the server goes into an
程序，然后服务器进入一个
into a loop and in each iteration it it
成一个循环，并在每一次迭代它它
gets the size of the socket or storage
得到插座或存储的大小
type and puts it into client client lend
键入并把它放到客户端出借
and then it calls it except with
然后调用 它除了具有
pointers to the to the clients address
指针指向到客户端地址
and in client one using the listening
并在客户端使用一个聆听
descriptor that was returned by open
这是open返回描述符
listened FD the accept call after it
听了FD的接受后，呼叫
gets a connection request it returns
得到它返回一个连接请求
with the address of the client that made
与生产该 客户端 的地址
the DD that at the other end of the
的DD，在的另一端
connection along with the DP at the true
在真实 与 DP 连接一起
length of that of that address so the
的那该地址的长度，因此
case of ipv4 before four bytes
的IPv4的情况下， 前四个字节
and then the accept returns this
然后接受退货， 这
disconnected file descriptor that the
断开连接的文件描述符的
then that that the the child that they
那么该孩子，他们
can use to to read and write and
可以用它来读取和写入和
interact with their client so it creates
与 他们的客户端交互，因此产生
say it works the child and then the
要说它的工作原理孩子，然后
child closes it's listening descriptor
孩子关闭 它监听的描述符
and then it calls the echo routine to
然后调用回声例程
interact with thee to interact with the
与你交流与互动
client and when the echo routine returns
客户端和当回声例程 返回
the client closes this connected
客户端关闭连接这
descriptor and then exits and so this
描述，然后退出，所以这
close isn't isn't absolutely necessary
关闭不是没有绝对必要
but we just did it to be careful okay
但我们这样做是为了 要小心好吗
now the parent and this is important
现在的父母 ，这是很重要
closes the connected descriptor because
关闭上述连接描述符，因为
it's not going to use that connected
它不会使用该连接
descriptor only the child will use that
仅描述孩子 将使用
connected descriptor so in order to
连接描述符所以为了
avoid this a memory leak it's very
避免这种内存泄漏是非常
important for the child to to close this
重要的是， 孩子要关闭此
descriptor okay because remember this
描述没关系，因为记得这
the server's running in an infinite loop
服务器的无限循环运行
I mediate in in theory it would never it
我 在理论上调解它永远不会是
would never terminate okay and then and
永远不会结束好，然后和
then to avoid done and to avoid a memory
那么要避免 做，以避免内存
leak we have to in our handler we have
漏，我们必须在我们的处理程序，我们有
to have a sick child handler that will
有一个生病的孩子处理程序，它会
will reap all of the children that have
将获得所有有孩子的
terminated okay so let's look a little
终止好吧，让我们来看看一点点
more detail how this how this except
更详细的如何如何 除
works so you have a client with a client
工作让你有一个客户端与客户端
file descriptor and then you have a
文件描述符，然后你有一个
server that creates a listening
创建一个监听服务器
descriptor so let's say that's you know
描述让我们说，就是你知道
descriptors are indexed by small
描述由小索引
integers so let's say that that index is
整数让我们说， 索引为
three the description number is three so
三个描述数量为 三个，从而
the server block can accept waiting for
服务器模块可以接受等待
is connection request the client makes a
是连接请求客户端发出
connection request using the connect
使用连接的连接请求
call
呼叫
okay the server accepts the connect call
还好服务器接受连接调用
and then it creates a child and then the
然后它创建一个孩子，然后
child interacts with the client using
孩子使用与客户端的交互
the connected file descriptor that was
这是连接的文件描述符
returned from the accept so that would
从返回的接受，这样会
be saved descriptor number four just be
保存描述符排名第四的只是
some different number okay start the
一些不同的号码好开始
execution model we have four these
执行模型中 ，我们有 四个这些
process based servers is that we have
过程的服务器是我们有
the the server processor listening for
在服务器处理器监听
connection requests one after the other
连接后，其他请求一个
from clients and then we have multiple
从客户端 ，然后我们有多个
clients interacting concurrently with
客户同时交互
with multiple children interacting
有多个孩子互动
concurrently with multiple clients okay
同时与多个客户端 没关系
since each of these each of these
因为每个这些的这些各
children are processes there's no shared
孩子的过程有没有共享
state between them and both parent and
他们两家母公司之间 的状态
child inherit the have they inherit the
孩子继承有他们继承
descriptor table so they have they both
描述符表让他们有他们都
have copies of listen FD and and and the
有听FD的副本，并与
listening descriptor in the connected
在连接监听描述符
descriptor okay and as we saw before the
描述好吧，当我们以前看到的
parent must close its its copy of the
父母必须关闭 其旗下的副本
connected file descriptor the child
连接文件描述符孩子
should close the listening descriptor
应关闭监听描述符
but it's you know just to be just
但它是你知道 刚才是公正
because it's not needed all right when
因为它不需要没事 的时候
you so these are actually pretty simple
你那么这些实际上是非常简单的
to create there's just a couple of
创造有只是一对夫妇 的
things you have to keep in mind when you
事情你必须要记住 你的时候
when you build a process based server so
当你建立一个基于流程的服务器，以便
firstly as we as with any any process
首先，我们与任何任何 进程
that creates children it has to reap
创建 它有 收获 的孩子
these children that are terminated to
这些孩子被终止
avoid this memory leak the parent
避免此内存泄漏的父
process has to close its copy of a
过程必须关闭其副本
connected file descriptor and there's a
连接文件描述符， 有一个
couple reasons its effect if it doesn't
如果没有几个方面的原因其效果
it will not only create a memory leak
它不仅会 创建一个内存泄漏
but that
但
the state associated with that
与之相关的状态
descriptor will actually stay around
描述实际上将呆在身边
forever because the the kernel won't
永远，因为内核 不会
close that connection so it as we saw
关闭连接，因此，我们看到
when we looked at at file i/o now this
当我们看着在文件I / O现在这
is just enough this is the same kind of
是刚够本是同种
file i/o we looked at before so the
文件I / O，我们看着面前的 ，因此
kernel keeps a reference count for each
内核维护每个引用计数
each socket that's open so after the
每一个的开放套接字打完
fork now there's there's two there's a
叉现在有有两家有一个
parent and the child which are accessing
父母和 正在访问 的 孩子
the file table associated with the
与相关的文件表
connected file descriptor okay so that
连接文件描述符还好使
and the connection won't be closed until
和连接不会被关闭，直到
the reference count for that connected
对于所连接的引用计数
file description is zero right so the
文件描述是 正确的零，因此
that file table entry won't be removed
该文件表项不会被删除
from the kernel until until there's only
从内核直到直到只剩有
there until there's zero references to
在那里，直到有零个引用
it okay so both the parent and the child
它好了，所以家长和 孩子 都
have to close that that descriptor
要关闭该描述符
okay now the good thing about process
现在没事了有关过程的好事
based servers is that they do the job
基于服务器的是，他们做的工作
for us that we asked them to do right we
对我们来说，我们 要求他们做对我们
wanted them to handle to interact with
希望他们来处理与 互动
multiple clients concurrently or have
多个客户端同时 或有
that ability there's a very clean
这种能力 有一个非常干净的
sharing model right so there's private
共享模式右所以有私人
address spaces between the any all of
在 任何所有的 之间的地址空间
the children and the parent they share
孩子们和他们 分享 父
they have separate descriptors but they
它们有不同的描述，但他们
share their separate copies of the
分享他们的单独的副本
descriptor table but they share the same
描述符表，但它们共享相同的
Open File table okay
打开文件 表好吗
and there's so in some sense this is a
而且在某种意义上，这是一个这么
simplest possible way to create a
最简单的方式来创建
concurrent servers and if you can get
并发服务器，如果你能得到
get if you can get by with not sharing
获得如果你能不能分享度日
any global variables or sharing address
任何全局变量或共享地址
spaces then this is this is the way to
空间，那么这是这 是必经之路
go
走
the disadvantage is that if there's
缺点是 ，如果有 那
additional overhead for processes even
对于流程的额外开销，甚至
even with this copy-on-write trick that
即使有这样的写入时复制的技巧，
we saw for sharing the sharing the dress
我们看到了分享分享礼服
space between the parent and the child
家长和孩子之间的空间
still it's still non-trivial overhead
还是它仍然是不平凡的 开销
and it's you have to actually do a lot
它是你必须 真正做了很多
of work if you want to share data
工作的，如果你想共享数据
between processes so like let's say you
流程之间 ，就像我们说你
want to have some kind of a shared cache
希望有某种 共享缓存
between multiple processes you either
多进程之间你要么
have to use file ok on disk or if you
必须使用文件确定 在磁盘上 ， 或者 如果您
want to share memory you have to use
要共享内存，你必须使用
some kind of you have to choose use some
某种你必须 选择使用一些
kind of memory mapping or you have to
一种内存映射， 或者你必须
use what's these inter process
使用什么是这些进程间
communication mechanisms which we
沟通机制，我们
haven't we haven't talked about but
我们不是还没有谈到，但是
there's there's ways pipes are probably
有有办法管可能是
the ones you're most familiar with so a
那些你是 最熟悉 所以
pipe allows one process to to send data
管允许一个进程来发送数据
to another process and there's ways to
到另一个进程 ，并有办法
share memory between processes but
过程，但之间共享存储器
they're they're cumbersome and require I
他们是他们是累赘，需要我
have to be implemented with care ok now
必须认真确定现在执行
the second approach is is we call an
第二种方法则是我们所说的
event based server so the idea here is
基于事件的 服务器这样的想法是在这里
that the server maintains a set of
服务器维护一组
active connections so it it it has an
活动的连接，因此它具有一个
array of connected file descriptors from
从连接文件描述符阵列
different clients ok and then it
不同的客户确定，然后将其
determines which of those and it also
确定哪些那些 和它的也
has a listening descriptor and then it
具有听描述符，然后将其
determines which of those descriptors
确定哪个那些描述符的
have pending input and it determines
有挂起的输入，它决定
this using a system call called select
这个使用系统调用叫做选择
or equal there's several ways to
或者等于有几种方法
determine this
确定此
but but basically using select or equal
但但基本上使用选择或 等于
you can determine which of a set of
你能 确定一组的
descriptors has pending input and then
描述符已经挂起的输入，然后
this this and so the arrival of input at
此这一点，所以输入的到达在
a descriptors is called an event because
一个描述符被称为因为某个事件
it changes the state as a descriptor
它改变了国家 作为一个描述符
okay so an event is always event in
好了，所以事件总是在事件
general is always some kind of state
一般总是某种 状态
change so in this case when data arrives
在这种情况下发生变化，所以当数据到达
on a socket that's a change into the
在一个插座，这是一个改变 成
state so there was no data before the
状态，这样有前无数据
event after the event now there's data
事件的事件现在有数据 后，
that the server can read so if if the
该服务器可以读取，所以如果当
listening descriptor has input then the
听完描述符输入，则
server calls accept to accept the
服务器调用accept接受
connection and for all and then all
连接并为所有 ， 然后所有
connected descriptors that have pending
连接描述符具有挂起
inputs it services those it reads from
它输入服务那些从读
those in some order okay now that the
那些以某种顺序 现在没事 了
details for how to do this or described
对于如何做到 这一点或描述细节
in the book but basically I mean the
在书中，但基本上我的意思是
conceptually it's pretty simple it's
概念上它非常简单，它是
actually tricky to implement but the
实际上棘手的 实施 ，但
idea is that there's some set of active
想法是，有一些集的活跃
descriptors right there's some set of
描述正确的有一些集
descriptors connected descriptors that
描述连接描述符
you're using that are being used right
您正在使用 正在使用权
now to to interact with a client there's
现在进行互动与客户有
some that are inactive so if descriptors
一些是无效的，所以如果描述符
descriptor was closed then it's it's no
描述被关闭那么它是没有
longer active right and then there's
再主动权 ，然后有
other descriptors that have never been
其它的描述从未被
used so we just have this array of
用，所以我们只是有这个数组
descriptors and then and then we record
描述， 然后，然后我们记录
their you know the the descriptive
他们 你知道 的描述
number for each of those connected for
为每个连接 用于 数
each of those descriptors
每个这些描述符
and then using select or eople or some
然后使用select或eople或一些
other mechanism we somehow determine
其他机制我们以某种方式确定
which of those active descriptors have
其中那些活性描述符的有
input and then we service each of those
输入，然后我们每个服务的那些
in the case of listen fde by calling
在的情况下， 通过调用听FDE
except in the case of these connected
除了在这些连接的情况下
descriptors actually these are this
实际上描述这些都是本
should be con FD not client empty but in
应CON FD不是客户端为空，但在
the case of these connected descriptors
这些连接描述符的情况下
we we read the data from them and the
我们我们从他们和读取数据
when we when we read the data from each
当我们，当我们读取每个数据
each descriptor we do some work okay so
每一个描述符，我们做了一些工作好了，
so data arrives at a descriptor and then
所以数据到达一个描述符，然后
we read that data and then we do some
我们读到的数据， 然后 我们做了一些
kind of work maybe in the case of an
这种工作也许在 的 情况下
echo server we echo it right back okay
我们呼应它的右后卫没关系回声服务器
in the case of a web server we may if
在Web服务器的情况下，我们如果
that data was HTTP request we might go
该数据是HTTP 请求，我们可能会去
in such a file from disk and return it
从磁盘这样的文件，并将其返回
okay but but in any case we we noticed
不错，但但在任何情况下，我们，我们注意到
that the descriptor has some data we
该描述符有一些数据，我们
read that data and then we respond to it
读取数据，然后我们对此作出回应
in some way ok so that response those
以某种方式确定，这样，响应者
multiple responses are concurrent flows
多个响应是并发流
okay the the when we're interacting with
没事 的 时候 在 我们正在 与 互动
that client we're interacting we're
该客户端，我们互动，我们是
creating concurrent flows while
创作的时候并发流
concurrent flow for each each client and
每个每个客户端的并发流和
we're servicing those clients
我们服务这些客户端
concurrently ok so even though it's a
同时确定，所以即使它是一个
sequential program right we're not using
我们 不使用 串行 程序的权利
fork or anything it's a it's just a C
叉或任何这是一个它只是一个C
program straightforward C program we're
程序简单的C程序 我们
writing in such a way that we're
写这样的方式 ，我们是
creating our own concurrent flows
创建自己的并发流
so there's a as with any any approach
所以有与任何任何方法
there's there's advantages and
还有的有优势，
disadvantages so that a big advantage of
缺点使的一大优势
event based servers is that it's just
基于事件的服务器是，它只是
lets acquaintance it's one process with
让相知 是一个过程与
the st. with one address space right so
圣。同一个地址空间的权利，使
it's very easy you can use conventional
这是很容易的，你可以 使用传统的
debugger gdb to step through you can see
GDB调试器来逐步可以看到
everything you have access to everything
一切你有机会获得一切
so in that sense they're much simpler to
所以在这个意义上，它们是更简单
debug understand and then there's no
调试了解 后再也没有
process or thread control overhead so
进程或线程控制开销等等
when we when we serve us a particular
当我们的时候，我们为我们服务的特定
descriptor it's very it's there's very
描述这是非常它的存在是非常
little overhead right we just the only
小的开销正确的，我们只是唯一的
overhead is sort of determining that
开销排序确定
that descriptor has input available ok
该描述符输入可确定
and so because of that this is the high
所以 ，因为这是 高
performance web servers like god no js'
性能Web服务器像神没有JS'
nginx tornado they all use this event
nginx的龙卷风都使用这个事件
based approach case if you want to get
如果你想获得基础的方法的情况下
over 10,000 10,000 requests per second
每秒超过10,000 10,000请求
you have to go with something like this
你必须去 像这样 的 东西
ok the disadvantage is it's much harder
OK缺点是它的更难
to more complex to to code up than the
更复杂，比代码了
other processor thread based designs and
其他处理器线程为基础的设计和
it's very difficult so one of the
它是非常困难这样的一个
hardest aspects aspects of a writing an
的书面 的最难方面方面
event based server is that you have to
基于事件的服务器， 你必须
figure out how much work you're going to
找出 你多少工作会
do in response to an event ok so let me
不要在响应 事件 确定，所以让我
give you let's say this server is a web
给你让我们说这个服务器是一个网络
server and you get input on it on one of
服务器和你 输入的它 的一个
your connected file descriptor the
您连接的文件描述符
simplest the simplest thing to do would
简单到最简单的做法 会
be to then assume to read the entire
是再假设读取整个
HTTP request and not and not return
HTTP请求，而不是 不回
until you've read the entire request
直到你读完整个请求
okay so in that case the the amount of
好了，所以在这种情况下，该量
work that you do in response to an event
您在响应做事件工作
is very coarse-grained there's a lot of
非常粗粒有很多的
instructions because we're going to read
指令，因为我们马上要读
every single every single line and that
每一个每 一个线和
HD
HD
P requests header but it's so that's
P请求 头，但它是如此这
course that's an example of course
当然，这是当然的例子
screen it's very simple because every
屏幕这是 因为每一个 很 简单
time you get a request on the connected
时间你所连接的请求
descriptor you just read the whole you
描述你刚才读整你
just read the whole HTTP request and
刚看完整个HTTP请求和
then send a response
然后发送一个响应
okay so there's on the other hand its
好了，有一个在另一方面 它
vulnerable because what if a client
脆弱的，因为如果有什么客户端
misbehaves and doesn't send the entire
行为不端，不发送整个
HTTP requests what if it sends half of
HTTP请求什么，如果它发出的一半
these requests so if you were doing a
这些请求，所以如果你在 做一个
design an event based web server you
设计一个基于 事件 的Web服务器，你
probably wouldn't want to do that right
可能不希望这样做的权利
because that a single client wiii be
因为单个 客户 WIII是
back in the situation we were before
回来的情况我们之前
where a single misbehaving client could
在一个单一的行为不端的客户端可以
sort of shut down the whole server so
排序关闭 整个服务器，以便
you might say well I'm going to I'm
你可能会说好了我要去 我
going to my unit of work that I do in
去我工作的单位，我在做
response to a request will be to read a
响应于请求将 读取
single line from the request
从请求单线
okay so I'll read a single line and then
好了，所以我会读一个单一的 线 ，然后
I'll and then I'll return okay so every
我会，然后我会 没事 返回 所以每
so now we're in early evening reading
所以现在我们在傍晚阅读
single lines and once I've read the
单 线条有一次我读过
entire request then else then I'll send
整个请求，那么别的话，我会送
the response so that's better right so a
响应所以这是更好的权利，使一个
misbehaving client if it's sending like
行为不端的客户端，如果它像发送
whole whole text lines at a time even if
整个整个文本行，在即使 时间
it stops halfway through we'll still be
它中途停止通过 我们仍然会
able to make progress in service other
能够使 其他服务 的进展
other clients so that's a finer grained
其他客户端，这样的晶粒更细
approach it's better it's probably more
接近它的更好它可能更多
robust than waiting for the whole the
不是等待 整个健壮
whole request but it's still vulnerable
整体要求，但它仍然是脆弱的
because the client could just send a
因为客户端可以 只将
partial line so now we're back so really
部分行所以现在我们又回来了所以真的
the only way to write a robust event
写一个强壮的 事件的唯一途径
based web server is to be able to handle
基于web服务器是能够 处理
partial lines just read when there's
部分线路刚读时，有
data available on a on a on a descriptor
在一个描述符上的可用数据
you just read whatever data is available
你刚才读什么数据是可用
you remember how much you read if it's
你还记得你读了多少，如果它是
not a whole line you somehow have to
不是一整行，你无论如何都 必须
remember that you have to buffer it your
请记住，你必须缓冲它你
mem
MEM
Britt so now it's getting really
布里特 所以现在它变得非常
complicated right but that's what you
复杂的权利，但就是你
that's the price you pay for this for
这就是你为此付出的价格
this low overhead sort of easier to
这种开销排序低的更容易
debug kind of kind of model and then
调试那种类型的模型，然后的
another disadvantage is that you can't
另一个缺点是，你不能
since it's really a sequential program
因为它是一个真正的顺序程序
right it's one C program you can't take
右侧是一个C程序，你不能拿
advantage of multiple cores so the only
利用多内核所以唯一的
way to get sort of more performance out
的方式来获得某种 更表现出来
of something and event based servers
的东西 ，基于事件的服务器
just to replicate copies of that server
只是复制该服务器的副本
but you can't make an individual server
但你不能让一个单独的服务器
go faster by using multiple cores okay
走得更快通过使用多核好吗
the third approach is to use threads to
第三个方法是使用线程
create these concurrent flows it's very
创建这些并发流是非常
similar to processes but there's some
类似的过程，但有 一些
important differences so let's look
重要的分歧，让我们来看看
first at what we mean by a threads so
首先在我们所说 的一个线程这样 的意思
let's go back I'm going to let's go back
让我们回到我打算让我们回去
in and look at the traditional view of a
在看看的传统观点
process so we think of a process of some
过程因此我们认为的一些过程 的
context that's data structures in the
上下文的数据结构中
kernel ok data that the kernel keeps
内核OK数据，内核保持
about that process as well as this
有关此过程以及本
private address space which contains a
其中包含一个私有地址空间
stack code and data and then the stack
栈的代码和数据，然后将叠层
okay and then as part of the and then
没关系，然后作为 的，然后 部分
the the process context consists of
该进程上下文包括
context that's associated with the
这与相关的上下文
program like the registers condition
程序等 的寄存器状态
codes program counter stack pointer okay
代码的程序计数器堆栈指针没关系
and then it contains kernel context
然后它包含内核上下文
which is information in the kernel that
这是 在内核信息
the the kernel needs to to implement
该内核需要实施
this idea of a process okay so all of
一个进程的这个想法好了，所有的
the state is actually stored in the
国家实际上是存储在
kernel but some of the data is is
内核，但一些数据是是
directly associated with the program and
直接与节目 相关联 并
other other other data is sort of
其他以外的其他数据的排序
support data that the kernel needs to to
支持数据内核需要到
implement processes
实施过程
okay so let's just take this picture and
好了，所以让我们 只取 这幅画和
we're just going to just move things
我们只是刚刚搬东西
around a little bit so what I've done is
周围一 点点所以 我所做的就是
I've taken the stack off of the virtual
我已经采取 了堆栈关闭虚拟的
address space and sort of pulled it out
地址空间和形式的拉出来
along with a stack pointer and the the
连同 堆栈指针和所述
context that's associated with the
这与相关的上下文
program so the data registers the
程序，以便数据寄存器的
condition codes the stack pointer in the
条件码在堆栈指针
program counter okay and I've just
程序计数器可以的，我只是
renamed it thread context on stuttered
更名为线程上下文 结巴
program context but it's it's the same
程序上下文，但它是相同的
it's the same thing and then I'm going
这是同样的事情，然后我要去
to call this this whole thing the
调用此这件事的
combination of those of a stack and this
这些堆叠的和此组合
thread context I'm gonna call that a
线程上下文，我会打电话给一个
thread and then everything else remains
线程，然后一切遗体
the same it's we have we still have our
同样 是我们 有我们还是有 我们的
code and data and we have the kernel
代码和数据，我们 有内核
context key now by by doing this sort of
现在关键的 背景下 ，通过 做这样的
refactoring and just moving things
重构和刚搬东西
around
周围
I can now imagine so this stack isn't
现在我可以想像所以这个堆栈不
very much right it's so there's a
非常正确的它是如此有一个
there's this there's the stack space and
还有的这个有堆栈空间
then there's a little bit of data here
然后有数据 的一点点 在这里
in the form of some registers and some
在一些寄存器和一些形式
things to be stored but this is a fairly
要存储的东西，但是这是一个相当
small amount of data now when I reached
现在 的 数据我到达时， 少量
actor like this now I can I can think
像这样的演员现在我能我能 想到 的
about there being multiple threads
大约有是多线程
associated with the same process if I if
用同样的过程，如果我如果相关
I just keep different set of data thread
我只是不停组不同的数据线
context for each thread and then a
上下文为每个线程，然后
private a separate portion of the stack
所述堆叠的 私人的单独部分
that's associated with that thread so
一个与该线程这样关联
now each thread shares the same code and
现在每个线程共享相同的代码和
data the same virtual address space has
数据相同的虚拟地址空间具有
the same kernel context okay the same
相同的内核方面 还好 相同
i/o structures
I / O结构
but now it has it has its own separate
但现在它有它有自己独立的
individual stack okay so vocal local
个别堆好了，所以声音地方
variables things that you would store on
你会存储在变量的东西
a stack now would be would be private
堆栈现在是将私人
sort of independent and it has its own
那种独立的，它有自己的
set of its own program counter its own
它自己的程序集抗衡其自身
stack pointer its own set of registers
堆栈指针自己的寄存器的
and condition codes and then the one
和条件码，然后将一个
difference now is that each thread
现在不同的是，每个线程
instead of theirs there still a process
而不是 他们仍有 一个过程
ID for this process that's pointed part
ID为这个过程的尖端部
of the kernel context but each thread
内核上下文，但每个线程的
now has its own thread ID as part of its
现在都有自己的线程ID 作为其一部分
thread context okay so now the kernel
还好线程上下文所以现在的内核
can just treat each of these as separate
可以只是把每一种作为单独的
flows right there's a separate so it's
流动的权利有一个独立的所以它是
just like a process now the kernel can
就像这个过程现在内核 可以
remember where the each thread has its
记得那里的每个线程都有
own program counter and but they're
自己的程序计数器和 但他们
running code out of the same that coat
运行的代码出同 该涂层 的
the same code section in the in the
在在相同的代码部分
virtual address space so the sharing
虚拟地址空间，因此共享
code sharing data but they have their
代码共享数据，但他们有自己的
own program counter so they can the
自己的程序计数器，以便可以在
kernel can provide can create each of
内核可提供可创建各
these threads as a as a separate flow of
这些线程作为作为一个单独的流
control that it then schedules just like
控制它然后调度就像
it does of a process or in a similar way
它的过程中或以类似的方式
it does is a process but the difference
它是一个 过程，但不同的
is the reason the reason that for
是什么原因， 对于原因
threads in the first place is that when
摆在首位的线程是当
the colonel wants to contact switch from
上校想从触点开关
one thread to another there's not that
一个线程到另一个有没有说
much information that has to be saved
有要保存太多的信息
and restored it's just a small amount of
并恢复它的只是少量
data so the kernel has to save this the
数据，所以内核必须保存这个
data thread one context in some data
在一些数据数据线程一个上下文
structure some way and then restore the
结构的一些方式， 然后还原
context for thread too but we're talking
上下文线索太多，但我们谈论
about a very low overhead kind of
约一个非常低的开销样的
operation but it doesn't have to mess
操作，但它并没有乱
around with page tables virtual address
周围的页表的虚拟地址
space or any other of the process
空间或任何其他的方法的
context
上下文
so so threads are luck kind of like
所以这样线程是运气有点像
prophecies but they're different in the
预言，但他们在是不同的
sense that they share the same virtual
某种意义上说它们共享相同的虚拟
address space and unlike prophecies
地址空间和不同的预言
which are created by fork which creates
其由叉它创建创建
a strict process hierarchy threads are
严格的工艺层次线程
just pools you can think of threads as
只是池，你能想到的线程作为
pools of concurrent flows that access
访问并发流的池
the same code and data and then the
相同的代码和数据，然后将
current the kernel is responsible for
当前的内核负责
scheduling those flows and in a way that
调度 的方式那些流动和
so each flow gets gets time on the
所以每个流得到得到时间上的
processor so much like much like
处理器那么像很像
processes much like concurrent processes
过程很像并发进程
we say the two threads are concurrent if
我们说两个线程可以并行 ，如果
their flows overlap in time otherwise
它们的流 在时间上 重叠 ，否则
they're sequential so this is the exact
他们是 连续的，所以这是确切的
same example that I showed you when we
同样的例子，我发现你的时候，
looked at processes so here you have
看着流程，以便在这里你有
instead of three processes we have three
而不是三个过程，我们 有 三个
threads running it within the same
线程运行它在同
process
处理
thread a runs for a little bit and then
一个线程运行一点点， 然后
the kernel decides to swap it out and
内核决定换出来，
and run thread B so then thread B runs
和运行线程B这样的话线程B运行
for a little bit and then the kernel
一点点，然后内核
decides to give thread see some time so
决定给线程看到一些时间，所以
it it saves thread these contacts
它可以节省线程这些接触
restores thread sees context and sets
恢复线程看到上下文和套
the PC to the the PC value and thread
PC到PC值和线程
seeds context and so C runs and then the
种子上下文等C同时运行，然后将
kernel decides to give a some time again
内核决定再给予一些时间
so then a run some more so because
所以再运行更多一些 ，是因为
thread a and B overlap in time they're
线程和B在时间上重叠 他们
running concurrently B and C don't
同时运行B和 C不
overlap in time so they they're now
在时间上重叠，使他们他们现在
running concurrently but a and C are
同时运行，但A和C
concurrent because they overlap in time
同时，因为他们在时间上重叠
and so you can you also have the option
所以你可以，你也可以选择
if there's multi multiple course then
如果有多个多当然 然后
multiple threat a threat can run on each
多重威胁的威胁可以在每次运行
core so then you can have true
核心，那么你可以 有真正的
parallelism okay
并行好吗
okay so like I said threads and
好了，所以就像我说的线程和
processes are are similar ideas but in
过程是类似的想法，但在
the sense that they they each stage
这个意义上，他们自己每个阶段
confession thread and process
忏悔线程和进程
corresponds to some kind of logical flow
对应于某种逻辑流
and they can run concurrently with with
他们可以与同时运行
other flows and each is scheduled and
其它流，并且每个被调度和
context switched by the kernel but
背景内核切换，但
they're different because threads share
他们是不同的，因为线程共享
all code and data except their local
所有的代码和数据，除了当地
stacks and in fact those local stacks
堆栈而事实上那些地方堆
although they're each thread has its own
虽然他们每个线程都有自己的
it's really just sharing the same stack
它实际上只是 共享同一组
and so it's really the same portion of
因此它是真正的同一部分
the virtual address space it's just that
虚拟地址空间它只是
each each thread is assigned its own
每个每个线程分配其自己
part of that stack okay so even though
该堆栈的一部分， 好了，所以即使
threads have their own individual stacks
线程有自己单独的栈
since it's all part of the same virtual
因为它是在同一个虚拟的一部分
address space a thread can access the
地址空间中的线程可以访问
stack of any other thread if it's and
堆栈中的任何其他线程的，如果它是和
that's not a good thing to do but it's
这不是做一件好事 ，但它的
possible okay so prophecies don't share
可能好了，所以预言不共享
any of the state right they did they
任何国家的权利，他们做了他们
have their own private address spaces
拥有自己的私人地址空间
and threads are less expensive than
和线程比更便宜
prophecies the it's cheaper to create
预言了它的便宜 创建
them and the main reason is that there's
他们的主要理由是 ，有
just less context associated with the
与相关短短不到上下文
thread than there is as a process and so
线程比有一个过程，因此
in our system when we measure a bunch of
在我们的 系统中 ，当我们衡量了一堆
we just create and and wait for a bunch
我们只是创造和等待一堆
of creative process wakeboard process
创作过程中 的wakeboard过程
over and over again and then measure the
一遍又一遍， 然后测量
time turns out to be about twenty
时间真可谓是大约 二十
thousand cycles to create and reap a
一千 周期创建和谋取
process about ten thousand cycles to
过程近万周期
create and reap a thread
创建并获得一个线程
so that the kernel provides threads to
这样内核提供线程
us using an interface called P threads
我们使用称为 P螺纹 接口
POSIX threads so this is a fairly recent
POSIX线程，所以这是一个相当新的
standard that all all Linux UNIX systems
标准的，所有所有的Linux UNIX系统
and Windows Macintosh so every this is a
和Windows的Macintosh 所以每次这是一个
sort of standard POSIX standard for for
排序为标准的POSIX标准
manipulating threads so you can do
操作线程，这样就可以做
things like create and reap threads so
例如 创建和收获线程等等
there's this is sort of sort of like
有这有点有点像
fork and this is sort of like weight but
叉，这是有点像 ，但重量
not not quite because it doesn't create
不是不太，因为它不会产生
there's there's no hierarchy associated
还有的没有相关的层次
with these you can you could just like
这些，你可以，你可以只喜欢
get bid you can there's a function to I
取得竞标你可以有一个功能 ，我
to get your thread ID you can kill
让你的线程ID，你可以杀
threads so one thread can kill another
线程使一个线程可以杀死另一
thread a thread there's there's a
Thread线程有有一个
function to exit a thread beat the the
函数退出线程击败的
normal exit system call terminates all
正常退出系统调用终止所有
the threads and return is similar to P
螺纹和回报是类似与P
thread exit in the sense that just
在这个意义上线程退出，只是
terminates the current thread the thread
终止当前线程的线程
that that calls it and then there's ways
即调用它，然后有办法
to access synchronized access to shared
访问 共享同步的访问
variables which which we'll look at on
变量我们来看看，其上
Thursday more detail
周四更详细
okay so here's the pthreads hello world
好了，所以这里的并行线程的hello world
program you know your K in our book to
计划你知道在我们的书 你的 K 至
see the C reference manual that the very
参见C参考手册， 非常
first the very first thing that it does
首先第一 件事情是它
is it shows you how to write the
是它表明你如何 写
simplest possible C program called so
可能最简单的C程序调用，所以
the famous hello world program so that
著名的Hello World 程序，使
goes all the way back to like 1978 when
追溯到一路像1978年的时候
K in our book was first written but that
K 的我们的图书是首次编写但
that's caught on and and whenever we
这抓住了上，每当我们
like learn a new language or we learn a
就像学习一 门新语言或者我们学习
new concept we always write the hello
新的概念，我们总是 写问候
world program for that concept so the
对于这一概念的世界节目 ，因此
hello world program for threads this is
你好线程世界节目，这是
this is a simplest threads program that
这是最简单的线程程序
I can think of so I call it the hello
我能想到的，所以我把它叫做打招呼
world program for threads so this
线程使这个世界计划
program defines a function so Court by
程序定义了一个函数，以便 由法院
in POSIX a thread is actually executed
在POSIX 线程实际 执行
by executing the code in a function
通过在功能执行代码
called the thread regime okay and POSIX
所谓的线程 机制 好和POSIX
imposes this thread routine takes a
规定此线程程序需要
generic pointer as an argument
通用指针作为参数
optional generic pointer and it returns
可选的通用指针并返回
a generic pointer okay so anytime you
通用指针好了， 任何时候你
want to pass anything to a thread you
想什么传递给一个线程你
somehow got to pack up all that data
不知怎么收拾 所有的 数据
into a single object then you can take
成一个对象，那么你可以采取
an address up but it you can see that
地址了， 但 你 可以看到，
this is extremely general-purpose
这是极其通用
so our hello world program creates a
所以我们的Hello World 程序创建一个
thread by calling pthread create and we
线程通过调用并行线程创建和我们
say instead of a child we call this a
说的不是一个孩子，我们称此为
pure thread okay so that there's no
纯 线程好，这样有没有
parent-child relationship any any
亲子关系的任何任何
threads can threads can reap other
线程可以线程可以收获其他
threads whether they created those
线程是否他们创建的那些
threads or not okay so you don't have
螺纹或不行，所以你不必
the strict parent-child hierarchy
严格的父子层次结构
Pete that create creates a thread that
皮特创建创建一个线程
executes the thread routine in this
执行此线程程序
third argument and returns the thread
第三个参数和返回线程
idea of that thread in the address and
在地址线的想法，
the integer pointed at by the first
整数指向由第一
argument the second argument is set up
参数 中的第二个参数被 设置
there's there's ways to set attributes
有有办法来设置属性
of threads but are beyond the scope of
线程， 但超出的范围
this course and will always just have
这门课将永远只是有
those no and then that this fourth
那些没有然后，这个第四
argument is the optional argument that
参数是可选的说法，
you want to pass to your thread routine
你想传递给你的线程程序
okay so in this case we're saying call
好了 ，所以在这种情况下，我们说的呼叫
the thread routine that's that's called
就是这样就是所谓的线程程序
thread with no arguments and then our
不带任何参数 ，然后我们的线程
thread routine just prints out hello
线程程序只是打印出打招呼
world and then it returns in this case
世界，然后返回 在这种情况下，
it doesn't return anything so it returns
所以它返回它不返回任何东西
null but if we wanted to return
空 但如果我们想 回
something to the to the calling program
东西向的调用程序
we could have returned something on a
我们可以 返回的东西在
pointer to some generic object okay
指针一些通用对象好吗
okay so the thread ID the thread
好了，所以线程ID线程
attributes are null that the thread
属性是空的 线程
routine the thread arguments are void
常规的螺纹参数是无效
star T and the return value is a void
星T和返回值是无效
double so at the pointer to the pointer
在指针的指针加倍，这样
that you want to return okay all right
要返回还好没事
so let's look at what happens when we
所以让我们来看看我们什么时候会发生什么
execute hello world so the main thread
执行的hello world 所以主线程
runs for a while then it calls
运行了一会儿，然后调用
pthread create which creates the pure
并行线程创建它创建了纯
thread which now is a concurrent flow
螺纹现在是顺流
that's running once once the pthread
这一度的并行线程运行一次
create returns then we're running two
创造收益，然后我们运行两个
concurrent flows or running the main
并发流或运行主
thread and we're running the the peer
线程，我们正在 运行的同行
thread
线
and so in this case our hello world
所以在这种情况下，我们的Hello World
waits for the pier threads are finished
在码头等待的线程都完成
by calling pthread join the peer-to-peer
通过调用并行线程加入了对等网络
thread after the calls its printout that
调用 它的打印输出后的线程
returns know which terminates the thread
返回 知道这会终止线程
at that point the P thread join returns
在这一点上在P螺纹联接返回
and the main thread continues
而主线程继续
okay so using it using these create this
好了，所以用它利用 这些创造这个
create function how would we write a
创建功能，我们会怎么写
thread based concurrent echo server and
基于线程的并发回显服务器和
again it's very similar to the way we
再次是非常相似的方式，我们
did it with the process based design so
与基于过程的设计，这样做的
we call we acquire a listening
我们呼吁我们获得了一个监听
descriptor by calling our oh-seok and
通过拨打我们的哦硕描述符和
listen FD function just as before and
听FD功能，就像之前
then inside this infinite server loop we
那么这个无限循环的服务器里面我们
we get the size of the we get the size
我们得到了我们的大小获得大小
of the client adder struct so which is
客户端加法器结构， 以便其是
which is going to be a large enough to
这将是一个足够大
fit any address and then we we malloc
适合任何地址，然后我们我们的malloc
space for the connected file descriptor
为所连接的文件描述符空间
so we're making a one integer sized
所以我们正在做的一个整数大小
portion of dynamic storage for this
该动态存储的部分
connected descriptor that were that
将原本连接描述符
we're going to get back from accept and
我们要得到 接受回来
we're going to this is actually really
我们要这其实是真的
important to avoid a nasty race
重要的是避免讨厌的种族
condition I'll show you in a second so
条件我会在第二展示你这么
now we call accept with our listening
现在我们所说的我们的听音接受
descriptor and client address and client
描述和客户端地址和客户端
length just like before and accept
长像以前一样 接受
returns the connected descriptor and
返回连接描述符 和
then we dereference this connected
那么我们这个解引用连接
descriptor pointer and so and store that
描述指针等和商店
the value returned by except in this in
除了在这返回的值
this location in the heap and then we
这个位置在堆中 ，然后我们
call t thread create by giving it the
叫牛逼线程通过给创建它的
name of our thread routine which in this
我们的线程程序 的名称 ，在这种
case is just simply a function we
情况是只是简单的功能 我们
defined in our program called thread and
在我们的程序中调用线程定义
the pointer to the connected file
指针到所连接的文件
descriptor
描述
okay now our client which our client
还好 我们的客户，我们的客户 现在
which our thread routine that we'll use
其中我们的线程程序，我们将使用
to interact with the client okay so the
与客户 互动 还好使
thread routine dereferences the argument
线程程序取消引用参数
remember is a pointer to a connected
记住 的是一个指针指向一个连接
file descriptor so it D references that
文件描述符所以三维引用 的是
pointer to get the to get the actual
指针，以获得获得实际的
integer connected descriptor and then it
整数连接描述符，然后将其
detaches the thread so by default
分离线程 所以默认
threads thread threads run an
线程的线程的线程运行
independent in attached mode so they can
独立 于附模式，以便它们可以
be you know they can be joined by other
是你知道他们可以 通过其他被连接
threads and they can be killed by other
线程，它们可以被其他被杀死
threads but by default it's similar when
线程但默认 情况下它是类似的，当
when threads are running in sort of
当线程排序的运行
unattached mode you can or on detached
独立的模式，你可以或分离
mode then they when they when they die
模式，则他们时，他们当他们死
they have to be reaped by a join
他们必须通过加入来收获
function to to acquire those resources
函数来获取这些资源
but if we detach a thread then it can't
但是，如果我们去除一个线程 话，就不能
be it can't be joined by any threads but
可它不能被任何线程加入，但
when it dies the kernel will
当它死的内核
automatically restore the the resources
自动恢复的资源
associated with that thread so in this
与线程，以便在此相关
case we're going to just detach this
情况下，我们将只是这个分离
thread so we're not to worry about
螺纹所以我们不担心
reaping it when it does when it finishes
收获它，当它完成它什么时候
and then we're going to free this this
然后我们要 释放此本
memory that was malloc
内存是的malloc
so this is important we have to free
所以这是非常重要的，我们必须 释放
this memory that was malloc by the the
该内存由 该 为的malloc
main thread in order to avoid a memory
为了避免存储器主线程
leak and then we we call our echo
漏，然后我们，我们调用回声
function so we interact with the the
功能，所以我们跟 的 互动
echo client until the echo clients
回声客户，直到客户的回声
finished and then we close this
完成，然后我们关闭这个
descriptor again to avoid a potentially
再次描述符避免潜在的
fatal memory leak
致命的内存泄漏
so this thread based execution model is
所以这种基于线程的执行模型 是
very similar to the execution model that
非常相似 的执行模型
we saw with with prophesies so we have a
我们与预言看到，所以我们有一个
list of domain thread that's listening
域线程的列表在 听
for connection requests we were waiting
连接请求我们等待
for connection requests via accept and
对于通过接受和连接请求
then we have for each client we have a
然后我们对每一个客户，我们有 一个
peer thread that interacts with that
以该相互作用对螺纹
client using the connected descriptor
使用所连接的客户机的描述符
that was passed in when we created the
这是在我们创建的经过时
thread and then each thread has its own
线程，然后每个线程都有自己的
since it has its own stack it has it has
因为它有它自己的堆栈它有它
separate space for its local variables
它的 局部变量独立的空间
and this is really the powerful thing
这 是真正的强大的东西
about threads now we can with these
有关线程现在我们可以用这些
things they by declaring these local
的东西，他们通过声明这些地方
variables we can we can create threads
变量，我们可以，我们可以创建线程
that won't interact with each other and
不会互相影响 和
won't and can run independently yes
不会，也独立运行是
surrounding the action thinking always
周围的动作 总是想着
I guess yeah the question is is there
我想 是的，问题是有没有
any time you wouldn't want to run
任何时候你不想跑
detached so when you run gee cash you
分离，所以当你 运行 哎呀你现金
give up the the power to kill other
放弃权力杀死其他
threads so so I don't know it's just
螺纹，所以我不知道这只是
it's hard to it's hard to come up with
很难很难拿出
good example right but but if you wanted
很好的例子，但 权 ，但如果你想
the ability to to be able to terminate
的能力，才能够 终止
other threads you know maybe if you had
你也许知道，如果你有其他线程
maybe if you if you were running a pool
也许，如果你，如果你正在运行一个游泳池
of like worker threads and at some point
像工作线程，并在某些时候
at some point if I mean I guess you
在某些时候，如果我说我想 你
could imagine a scenario where suppose
可以想象这里假设一个场景
you're running a pool of worker threads
您正在运行的工作线程池
you give them all jobs to do the first
你给他们的所有作业要做的第一件
one that finishes you take the result
一个 完成你把结果
and you don't need the results from the
你不需要从结果
other threads so you might you might
其他线程，这样就可能你 可能
just want to kill those threads but it's
只是想杀死那些线程，但它
yeah it's hard it's hard to come up with
是的，很难， 很难拿出
a really compelling reason
一个真正令人信服的理由
okay so there's a few things to think
好了，有 思考 的几件事
about when you're when you're writing
约当你你写的时候
thread based servers so the first is
基于线程的服务器，所以第一个是
that yet you need to run detach to avoid
那还需要运行分离，以避免
potential memory leaks I'm sorry I
潜在的内存泄漏对不起，我
forgot this word so it the opposite of
忘记这个词所以它的相对
detached is joinable and so joinable
超然是可连接，因此可连接
threads like a mention can be reaped and
像一个提线可以收获和
killed by other threads detached threads
其他线程分离线程丧生
cannot and their resources are
不能和他们的资源
automatically claimed on termination so
在终止时自动声称这样
the default states joinable and you have
默认状态可连接，你有
to use this detach function call to make
使用这种分离的函数调用进行
to make the thread detached the biggest
使分离线程最大
the biggest issue with threads so like
与 线程 的最大问题 ，所以像
the beautiful thing about threads is
有关线程的美丽的东西是
that you're sharing the same global
您在共享相同的 全局
address space so it's very easy to share
地址空间，所以它很容易分享
data structures you know if you had
你知道的数据结构，如果你有
multiple threads if you had a web server
多线程，如果你有一个Web服务器
a concurrent web server that was built
这是建并发 Web服务器
with multiple threads be very easy to
多线程是很容易
implement a cache that all the threads
实现一个高速缓存，所有的线程
could could use because they're all
可能可以使用，因为他们都
sharing that same virtual address space
共享相同的虚拟地址空间
but the thing that makes threads so nice
但是，使线程这么好看的东西
this ease the ease with which you can
这缓解难易程度 ，你可以
share resources is also the thing that
共享资源也是 件事
makes them very tricky to deal with so
使得他们非常棘手，处理这样
as soon as just like we saw with our
只要就像我们有看到了 我们
shell lab handlers you know as soon as
你只要知道壳实验室处理程序
you're as soon as you have multiple
你只要你有 多个 是
flows accessing shared resources it can
流访问共享资源 它可以
be very careful it's very easy to make
必须非常小心，它很容易 使
mistakes and it's very it's very easy to
错误，这是非常它很容易
or it's possible to to share resources
或者有可能共享资源
in unexpected in unintended ways for
在非预期的方式意外
example if if one if one thread passes
例如，如果如果如果一个线程传递
the address of a local variable on its
在一个局部变量的地址其
stack to another thread then now that
堆到另一个线程，然后现在
that the called thread now has access to
被叫线程现在可以访问
the callers thread and there's nothing
求助者线程并没有什么
to prevent that that call thread from
防止从 调用线程
manipulating local variables on the
操作上的局部变量
caller stack and that would be a very
调用程序堆栈，这将是一个非常
bad thing to do but it's possible you
坏的事情，但有可能你
might you might forget you know you
也许你可能会忘记你知道你
might you might forget the
也许你可能会忘记的
the variable you're passing is a local
你传递的变量是本地
variable not a not a global okay end up
变量不是不是全局 好吗落得
really bad mistake in our in our hello
非常糟糕的错误在我们我们打招呼
in our echo server example you know so
在我们的回声服务器的例子，你知道，所以
we were very careful to now like space
我们现在 非常 小心， 像空间
for this for this connected file
这此连接的文件
descriptor that we passed into the peer
我们传递给同行描述符
thread that we are creating would have
我们正在创建将有螺纹
been much easier just to pass the
容易得多只是 为了打发
address of the connected file descriptor
所连接的文件描述符的地址
into our peer thread be much easier but
到我们对螺纹容易得多 ，但
it would also be wrong
这也将是错误
can you see why okay let's say right
你可以看到为什么没关系，让我们说对不对
here when we call pthread create instead
在这里，当我们称之为并行线程 ，而不是 创建
of passing a pointer to a separately
的指针传递到一个单独
allocated region of the heat instead of
热， 而不是分配区域
doing that we just passed the address of
这样做，我们刚刚通过 的地址
the connected file descriptor same thing
连接的文件描述符同样的事情
right okay and then in our thread
右好，然后在我们的线程
routine we dereference that pointer to
日常我们解引用该指针
to get the connected file descriptor
获得连接文件描述符
okay if we just pass the address of the
没关系，如果我们 只是 传递 的地址
connected file descriptor this is real
连接的文件描述符，这是真实的
it's really bad can you see why yes it
这是非常糟糕的，你可以看到为什么是它
does okay that's true and why is that
不好吧这是真的，为什么是
bad I mean just
糟糕， 我的意思只是
that's yeah that's right so what what
这是的， 这是正确的那么什么什么
this is assuming listen to this by
这是 假设通过听这
testing the address of this connected
测试此连接的地址
file descriptor we're introducing a race
文件描述符，我们推出了一个竞赛
okay in the race what we're assuming
还好在比赛中有什么我们假定
that the peer thread will be able to
对端线程就能
dereference that pointer before the main
取消引用前的主要 是指针
thread goes back up and gets a new
线程再次进入并获得一个新的
connected file descriptor right so what
连接文件描述符权等什么
happens what happens right we can't in a
会发生什么情况 的权利，我们不能在
concurrent system we can't make any
并发系统，我们不能做任何
assumptions about how the kernel is
有关 内核是 如何设想
going to schedule things right we saw
要安排 正确的事情，我们看到
the same thing with prophecies so what
有 预言于是同样的事情 是什么
happens if after pthread create the main
如果发生之后并行线程创建主
thread runs instead of the peer thread
线程运行，而不是对线程
okay so we passed the we've passed the
好了，所以我们通过我们已经通过了
address of the connected file descriptor
所连接的文件描述符的地址
for this client that at that we accepted
此客户端 ， 在我们接受
the connection request from and then
从再连接请求
before the before the peer thread can
在同行线程才能前
dereference that argument we get a new
解引用这样的说法，我们得到一个新的
connected file descriptor okay
连接文件描述符好吗
and now the child run and it
现在孩子跑，它
dereferences that that descriptor but
解引用该描述符，但
what it gets now is the descriptor that
它 现在 得到 的是描述符
that's that's corresponding to the
这是一个的对应
second the second child not the first
第二老二不是第一
child so now we have two threads talking
孩子，现在我们有两个线程说话
to the same client using the same
使用相同的同一客户端
descriptor
描述
so do you see them help so it's very
所以你看到他们帮助所以很
tricky this is like a real subtle this
棘手的，这是像一个真正的微妙这
is an example of sort of subtle errors
是 那种 细微的错误 的一个例子
that you can introduce because of this
你可以 因为这个介绍
unintended sharing and it's cause the
意想不到的共享， 它是 导致
root cause is as you correctly pointed
根本原因是因为你正确地 指出
out is that the both sharing the same
出的是两个共享相同
memory on the caller stack yes in this
呼叫者内存堆栈 是在这
case of what you could do there's
你可以 在那里做 什么 的 情况下，
another there's another thing you could
另外还有一件事，你可以
do alright you could just pass the
你好吗，你可以 只通过
descriptor itself capably so you could
干练的描述符本身，所以你可以
just cast the descriptor to a generic
只投中描述的通用
pointer and just pass that and that
指针和公正的传递和
that's just kind of yucky though that
这 只是一种虽然那令人讨厌的
that would work because instead of
这将工作，因为不是
dereferencing it the child would would
解引用它的孩子会会
just use it directly
只需直接用它
okay so good that's good
好那么好，是很好的
okay the so the so the really good
好了所以所以 真正的 好
things with with threads is ease of
东西与线程是易于
sharing but that sharing also introduces
共享但共享还介绍
okay introduced introduces complications
没关系介绍介绍并发症
in fact deaths we're going to look at
其实死亡，我们要看看
ways to sort of control the sharing so
方式来排序的控制共享 ，以便
that's done so that we do so that we
这样做了，使我们这样做，我们
don't get unintended unintended sharing
没有得到意想不到的意外共享
okay so to summarize the the approaches
好了，总结的方法
to concurrency that that we've looked at
到 我们已经看了 并发
we have process based concurrency so
我们有一个基于过程并发所以
it's hard to share resources but it's
很难共享资源，但它
easy to avoid unintended sharing so in
容易避免意外共享，以便在
some ways it's safer and easier to
某些方面它更安全，更容易
program event based so it's it's very
计划基于事件的所以这是它非常
low-level very tedious you have to be
低级别非常乏味 ，你必须
very careful about how you the
非常小心你如何
granularity of the work that you do in
你在做 的工作的粒度
response to events but you have total
响应事件，但你必须总
control over scheduling so you can
在调度控制，所以你可以
decide which which descriptors you're
决定哪个哪个描述符你
going to service and in which order it's
去服务，并在其订购 它
it's since there's a single flow of
这是因为有一个单一的流
control you can debug it with a debugger
控制你可以使用调试器进行调试
but it doesn't make use of multi-core so
但它并没有 充分利用多核心的这样
there's a handful of trade-offs there
有取舍了一把有
with thread based systems it's very easy
基于线程的系统它很容易
to share resources but that that sharing
资源共享但该共享
can create problems of its own it's
可以创建自己的问题， 这是
fairly efficient compared to two
相比于两个相当高效
processors you don't have much control
处理器你没有太多 的控制
over the scheduling so just like we saw
在调度所以就像我们看到
you're not you can't really control
你不是你不能真正控制
which with which threads get executed in
这与线程得到执行
which order and it can be difficult to
该订单并将其可能难以
debug because there can be races that
调试，因为有可能是比赛
occur very rarely very infrequently and
发生极少极少 和
so the probability of sort of creating
所以那种创造的概率
one of those race conditions is
这些比赛的条件之一是
difficult
难
okay so that's it for today
好了，这就是它 的今天
tomorrow we'll look at thread based
明天我们将看看基于线程
servers in more detail and how to write
更详细和服务器如何写
thread based systems efficiently and
有效的基于线程的系统和
correctly
正确地